made.com 2017-11-19

# Our Cookie and Privacy Policy | MADE.com

## I. PRIVACY POLICY

Last updated: 14 October 2016 

###  1\. MADE.COM’S APPROACH TO PRIVACY 

1.1 www.made.com is a website operated by Made.com Design Limited (we, our, us). We are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy sets out how we collect, use and share information that identifies you or is associated with you (“personal information”). 

1.2 For the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998, we are the data controller of the personal information we hold about you. 

1.3 You should also be aware that we use cookies to store and access information whilst providing access to our site. You can find out more about our use of cookies in our Cookie Policy. 

###  2\. PERSONAL INFORMATION WE HOLD ABOUT YOU 

2.1 We collect personal information from you when you voluntarily submit information directly to us or our website. This can include information you provide when you register to use the site, create an account on our site, set up a profile on Unboxed and interact with other users, visit one of our showrooms, use a tablet or similar device in one of our showrooms, complete a form, provide feedback or reviews on our products or site, enter competitions through our site, correspond with us, purchase products from the site, subscribe to our email lists or respond to surveys or promotions. 

2.2 We also collect personal information indirectly from you such as information about the pages you look at on the site or the device you connect to the site with, or the products you add to your wishlist using a tablet or similar device in one of our showrooms. We may also collect personal information about you from third parties such as other users of the site. 

2.3 We describe the categories of personal information we collect in more detail below: 

(a) Contact details: such as your name, your email address, your telephone number and addresses associated with your account. 

(b) Profile information: such as your contact details (as above) and other any information you share when creating a profile on Unboxed. 

(c) Comments and opinions: such as comments and opinions you share on Unboxed, when you provide feedback or reviews on our products or site, or when you respond to our surveys, competitions and promotions. 

(d) Messages to us or between users: messages you send to us such as email and written correspondence and messages to other users using Unboxed. 

(e) Payment and transaction information: we will keep records of the products and services you purchase from us and the payment method you use for the transaction. 

(f) Unboxed login profile information: third-party service (e.g., Facebook) login details and profile information such as your log-in token, user name and photo and other information from that service as permitted by you and that service. 

(g) Your preferences: choices you make such as notification and messaging preferences or choices about how the site is displayed. 

(h) Information about products you have looked at: We collect information about the products that you have looked at on the site or in one or our showrooms, or that you have added to your basket on the site or to your wishlist on a tablet or similar device in one of our showrooms. 

(i) Information about how you use and connect to the online service: 

(i) We collect information about how you use the site such as the pages and links you access, the time you access the site and duration you are on it, the website you come to the site from or go to after leaving the site and selections and choices you make when using the site. 

(ii) We also collect information about the computer or other electronic devices you use to connect to the site such as details about the type of device (which can include unique device identifying numbers), its operating system, browser and applications connected to the site through the device, your Internet service provider or mobile network, your IP address and your device’s telephone number (if it has one). 

(iii) Typically, the information we collect about how you use or connect to the site is associated with your device and not you as a named individual. However, if you are logged into a registered account this information may also be associated with you directly. 

(j) Information about your location: Other than information you choose to provide to us, we do not collect information about your precise location. Your device’s IP address may help us determine an approximate location but this will be no more precise than the city, state or country you are using your device in. 

(j) Information about the location of purchases: We will display a catalogue image of any purchase through our site on a searchable map as a way of showing the approximate location of the delivery address you give when making a purchase. We do not disclose any personally identifiable information on our map and only display our catalogue image of the purchase you made by reference to the postcode of the delivery address. 

(k) Information about the location of purchases: We will display a catalogue image of any purchase through our site on a searchable map as a way of showing the approximate location of the delivery address you give when making a purchase. We do not disclose any personally identifiable information on our map and only display our catalogue image of the purchase you made by reference to the postcode of the delivery address. 

(l) Information provided by other users: Sometimes, other visitors to our site provide information that is associated with you. For example, other visitors may provide information that is associated with you when they invite you to use the website or through Unboxed. 

(m) Information provided by other organisations: Other organisations may provide information that we associate with you where they are lawfully permitted to share it, such as contact details, demographic data, or Internet navigation information. 

(n) Information from fraud and crime prevention organisations: If fraudulent or other criminal activity is suspected relating to your account, we may be provided with information by credit reference, fraud and crime prevention organisations. 

###  3\. HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION 

3.1 We will also use your personal information for the purposes specifically described below: 

(a) Contact details: we will use your contact details so that we can communicate with you directly about the products we sell and the service we provide and about queries, issues or concerns you or other users have. We may also use your contact details to send you, or to enable our marketing and business partners to send to you, information about products and services that may be of interest to you (such communications will be in accordance with your marketing preferences), including information sent on behalf of or by our marketing and business partners that we or they think you may find interesting. 

(b) Profile information: we use your profile information to provide our Unboxed service to you and ensure that you are able to interact with our users as permitted by the functionality of the service and your preferences. 

(c) Comments and opinions: we will use your comments and opinions to determine products and services that may be of interest to you and to provide our Unboxed service to you and ensure that you are able to interact with our users as permitted by the functionality of the service and your preferences. 

(d) Payment and transaction information: we will use payment and transaction information you provide to process payment for any product or service you purchase from us. We may also use the history of your transactions with us to determine products and services that may be of interest to you. 

(e) Messages to us or other users: we will use messages you send to us to help us respond to any query, issue or concern you raise and to provide our Unboxed service to you and ensure that you are able to interact with our users as permitted by the functionality of the service and your preferences. 

(f) Your preferences: we will use your preference settings for the purpose of providing notifications, messages, displaying the site and following other choices you are able to make about how the site is displayed to you. 

(g) Information about products you have looked at: we use this information to send you reminders and further information about these products. We will also use this information to determine products and services that may be of interest to you. 

(h) Information about how you use and connect to the online service: we use this information to present the site to you on your device. We will also use this information to determine topics, products and services that may be of interest to you. 

(i) Information about your location: we may use an approximate location to ensure content on the site is relevant to the city, state or country you are using your device in. We will not collect or track your exact location without your consent. 

(j) Information about the location of purchases: we use this information to show what types of purchases are being made in a particular area on a searchable map and to allow users to contact other users about their purchasers either directly through Unboxed or through us depending on your preferences 

(k) Information provided by other users: we will use your personal information that is contained in messages sent to us by other users to respond to any query, issue or concern they raise or to provide our Unboxed service to you and ensure that you are able to interact with our users as permitted by the functionality of the service and your preferences. We will use your personal information that is contained in forms submitted by other users to contact you, if they indicate you would like to receive a communication from us. 

(l) Information about fraudulent or criminal activity relating to your account: we will use information about fraudulent or criminal activity relating to your account for the purposes of preventing fraud or crime. 

(m) All personal information: will use all the personal information we collect to: (i) monitor and improve the site and our procedures and processes; and (ii) to help us develop new products and services. Our use of your personal information in this way will not result in information that was not previously publicly available being made public on the site. We will also not use information about fraudulent or criminal activity relating to your account in the development of new products and services. 

3.2 We may anonymise and aggregate any of the information we collect (so that it does not directly identify you). We may use anonymised information for purposes that include testing our IT systems, research, data analysis, improving the site, developing new products and features or displaying information about the purchases made via our site such as the most popular purchases or purchases based on an approximate location. 

###  4\. INFORMATION WE SHARE WITH THIRD PARTIES 

4.1 We may share your personal information with the following parties: 

(a) Our users: we and you may share your information with other users as part of our Unboxed service so you are able to interact with our users as permitted by the functionality of the service and your preferences. 

(b) Companies in the same group of companies as us: our subsidiaries (i.e. any organisation we own or control) or our ultimate holding company (i.e. any organisation that owns or controls us) and any subsidiaries it owns. These companies will only use your personal information in the same way as we can under this privacy policy. 

(c) Service providers, partners and advisors: third parties who provide a service to us, partner with us on marketing and other business activities, advise us or that we work with in other business capacities. For example, we use a third party delivery service to deliver any products you buy to your address. We may also pass your personal information to our marketing and other business partners and other carefully selected third parties who may wish to offer you other goods or services that we or they have identified as likely to be of interest to you. These third parties will only be allowed to use your personal information in accordance with our instructions or your marketing preferences (where applicable) and will be required to keep your information secure. 

(d) Purchasers of our business: personal information may be disclosed or transferred to buyers or prospective buyers of our business or any of our assets as part of the sale. 

(e) Law enforcement, regulators and other parties for legal reasons: third parties who we are under a legal obligation to disclose your personal information to or who we need to disclose your personal information to protect our rights, property or safety or the rights, property or safety of others, detect and investigate illegal activities and breaches of any agreement we have with you. 

4.2 We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to anyone else except as set out above. We may provide third parties with aggregate statistical information and analytics about users of the site but we will make sure no one can be identified from this information before we disclose it. 

###  5\. MARKETING AND ADVERTISING 

5.1 Email Marketing - From time to time we may contact you by email with information about our products and services. If you do not want us to send you email marketing, please let us know by sending an email to us at privacy@made.com. You can also unsubscribe from our marketing emails by clicking on the unsubscribe link (where available) in the emails we send to you. 

5.2 Email Notifications On Behalf of Users – We may send you notifications that users may wish to contact you about purchases you have made through our site. If you wish to speak to the user, you may do so by signing up to Unboxed. If you do not want us to send these notifications, please let us know by sending an email to us at privacy@made.com. 

5.3 Email Notifications About Your Order or Changes to the Services We Provide - We may send you email notifications in relation to your order or changes to the way we provide our services to you. 

5.4 Advertising on the Site and other Websites – We, or our advertising partners, may show advertisements to you on our site or on other websites. To do this we, or our advertising partners, may collect information about how you use the site or the types of other web pages, content and ads you, or others who are using the device you connect to the site, interact with, visit or view. The information collected might also include the IP address of the device you connect to the site or the e-mail address you provide to us or our website. We, or our advertising partners, use the information that is collected to make sure adverts you see either on the site or other websites or apps (where our partners have advertising space) are more relevant to you. 

5.5 The techniques our advertising partners use recognise the device or e-mail address you are using but are not aimed at you as a named individual. Typically cookies and similar technologies are used to provide this type of advertising. You can find out more about cookies and how to manage their use by reading our Cookie Policy. 

###  6\. STORING AND TRANSFERRING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION 

6.1 Cookies and Local Storage: we may store information (which may include personal information) locally on your device using cookies and other browser and application storage methods. For further information please see our Cookie Policy. 

6.2 International Transfers of your Personal Information: the personal information we collect may be transferred to and stored in countries outside of the jurisdiction you are in, including, in particular, outside the European Union. Some of these jurisdictions offer differing levels of protection in respect of personal information and may, in certain instances, be less protective than the jurisdiction you are typically resident in. We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. 

###  7\. ACCESSING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION 

7.1 If there is information you would like to access, please contact us using the contact details set out in the “Contact us” section below. Please provide as much information as you can about the information you are looking for and we will be happy to try and help you find it. 

###  8\. LINKS TO THIRD PARTY SITES 

8.1 The site may, from time to time, contain links to and from third party websites of our partner networks, advertisers, partner merchants, news publications, retailers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for their policies. Please check the individual policies before you submit any information to those websites. 

###  9\. CHANGES TO THIS POLICY 

9.1 We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time and so you should review this policy periodically. When we change this privacy policy in a material way, we will update the “last modified” date at the top of this Privacy Policy. Changes to this privacy policy are effective when they are posted on this page. 

###  10\. NOTICE TO YOU 

10.1 If we need to provide you with information about something, whether for legal, marketing or other business related purposes, we will select what we believe is the best way to get in contact with you. We will usually do this through email or by placing a notice on the site. The fact that we may send notices to you will not stop you from being able to opt out of certain types of contact as described in this Privacy Policy. 

###  11\. CONTACTING US 

11.1 Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Policy are welcome and should be addressed to [privacy@made.com](mailto:privacy@made.com) or Made.com Design Limited, 100 Charing Cross Road, London WC2H 0JG, Attn: Privacy Officer. 

##  II. COOKIE POLICY 

Last updated: 13 November 2015 

###  1\. SUMMARY 

This cookie policy explains what cookies are and how Made.com Design Limited ("we," “us” or “our”) uses them on www.made.com (our “site”). We encourage you to read the policy in full so that you can understand what information we collect using cookies and how that information is used. By using our site you are agreeing that we can use cookies in accordance with this Cookie Policy. 

###  2\. WHAT ARE COOKIES? 

Cookies are text files, containing small amounts of information, which are downloaded to your browsing device (such as a computer or smartphone) when you visit a website. Cookies can be recognised by the website that downloaded them — or other websites that use the same cookies. This helps websites know if the browsing device has visited them before. 

###  3\. WHAT ARE COOKIES USED FOR? 

Cookies do lots of different jobs, like helping us understand how our website is being used, letting you navigate between pages efficiently, remembering your preferences, and generally improving your browsing experience. Cookies can also help ensure marketing you see online is more relevant to you and your interests. 

###  4\. WHAT TYPES OF COOKIES ARE USED BY MADE.COM? 

The types of cookies used on our site can generally be put into one of the following categories: strictly necessary; analytics; functionality; advertising; and social media. You can find out more about each of the cookie categories in the table below. 

Strictly Necessary Cookies 

| 

These cookies are essential to make our website work. They enable you to move around the site and use its features. Without these cookies, services that are necessary for you to be able to use our site such as accessing secure areas cannot be provided.   
  
---|---  
  
Analytics Cookies 

| 

These cookies collect information about how people are using our website, for example which pages are visited the most often, how people are moving from one link to another and if they get error messages from certain pages. These cookies don't gather information that identifies you. All information these cookies collect is grouped together with information from other people’s use of our site on an anonymous basis. Overall, these cookies provide us with analytical information about how our site is performing and how we can improve it.   
  
Functionality Cookies 

| 

These cookies allow us to remember choices you make and tailor our site to provide enhanced features and content to you. For example, these cookies can be used to remember your user name, language choice or country selection, they can also be used to remember changes you've made to text size, font and other parts of pages that you can customise.   
  
Advertising Cookies 

| 

These cookies are used to deliver advertisements that are more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign. They remember that you have visited a website and this information may be shared with other organisations such as advertising partners. This means after you have been to our site you may see some advertisements about our services elsewhere on the Internet.   
  
Social Media Cookies 

| 

In order to enhance your internet experience and to make the sharing of content easier, some of the pages on our website may contain tools or applications that are linked to third party social media service providers such as Facebook, Twitter or Google+. Through these tools or applications the social media service provider may set its own cookies on your device. We do not control these cookies and you should check the social media service provider’s website for further details about how they use cookies.   
  
You can see a list of some of the specific cookies which are most frequently used by us in Cookies Used by Made.com. 

###  5\. HOW LONG WILL COOKIES STAY ON MY BROWSING DEVICE? 

The length of time a cookie will stay on your browsing device depends on whether it is a “persistent” or “session” cookie. Session cookies will only stay on your device until you stop browsing. Persistent cookies stay on your browsing device after you have finished browsing until they expire or are deleted. Details of “persistent” and “session” cookies set through our website can be found on page Cookies used by Made.com. 

###  6\. FIRST AND THIRD-PARTY COOKIES 

“First party cookies” are cookies that belong to us and that we place on your device. “Third-party cookies” are cookies that another party places on your browsing device when you visit our site. Third parties setting cookies from our website will be providing a service to us or a function of the site but we do not always control how third party cookies are used. You should check the third party’s website for more information about how they use cookies. Details of third parties that set cookies through our website can be found on page Cookies Used by Made.com. 

###  7\. HOW TO MANAGE COOKIES FROM THIS WEBSITE 

You can usually use the browser that you are viewing this website through to enable, disable or delete cookies. To do this, follow the instructions provided by your browser (usually located within the “Help”, “Tools” or “Edit” settings). Please note that if you set your browser to disable cookies, you may not be able to access secure areas of the website and other parts of the website may also not work properly. 

You can find out more information about how to change your browser cookie settings at [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 

Some third parties may use Advertising Cookies to help gather information about your browsing activity so that they can deliver website advertising to you that is relevant to your interests. The advertising industries in EU have developed schemes to help you opt-out of receiving cookies used for these purposes. You can find out more about the EU scheme from [www.youronlinechoices.eu](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). 

###  8\. CHANGES 

Information about the cookies used by us may be updated from time to time, so please check back on a regular basis for any changes. The last modification date of this document is shown at the top of this page. 

###  9\. QUESTIONS? 

If you have any questions about this Cookie Policy, please contact us by email at privacy@made.com 

##  III. COOKIES USED BY MADE.COM 

Last updated: 31 July 2016 

The following tables and information set out the cookies which are most frequently used on our website. It also provides details of third parties that set cookies through our website. 

###  STRICTLY NECESSARY COOKIES 

**Cookie Provider**

| 

**Cookie Name**

| 

**First or third party cookie**

| 

**Persistent or**

**session cookie**

| 

**Purpose cookie used for**  
  
---|---|---|---|---  
  
Magento

| 

CART

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

The association with your shopping cart.  
  
CATEGORY_INFO

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Stores the category info on the page, that allows to display pages more quickly.  
  
COMPARE

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

The items that you have in the Compare Products list.  
  
CURRENCY

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Your preferred currency  
  
CUSTOMER

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

An encrypted version of your customer id with the store.  
  
CURRENCY

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Your preferred currency  
  
CUSTOMER_AUTH

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

An indicator if you are currently logged into the store.  
  
CUSTOMER_INFO

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

An encrypted version of the customer group you belong to.  
  
CUSTOMER_SEGMENT_IDS

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Stores the Customer Segment ID.  
  
EXTERNAL_NO_CACHE

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

A flag, which indicates whether caching is disabled or not.  
  
FRONTEND

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Your session ID on the server.  
  
GUEST-VIEW

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Allows guests to edit their orders.  
  
GUEST-VIEW

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Allows guests to edit their orders.  
  
LAST_CATEGORY

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

The last category you visited.  
  
LAST_PRODUCT

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

The most recent product you have viewed.  
  
NEWMESSAGE

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Indicates whether a new message has been received.  
  
NO_CACHE

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Indicates whether it is allowed to use cache.  
  
PERSISTENT_  
SHOPPING_CART

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

A link to information about your cart and viewing history if you have asked the site.  
  
POLL

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

The ID of any polls you have recently voted in.  
  
POLLN

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Information on what polls you have voted on.  
  
RECENTLYCOMPARED

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

The items that you have recently compared.  
  
STF

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Information on products you have emailed to friends.  
  
STORE

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

The store view or language you have selected.  
  
USER_ALLOWED_  
SAVE_COOKIE

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Indicates whether a customer allowed to use cookies.  
  
VIEWED_PRODUCT_IDS

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

The products that you have recently viewed.  
  
WISHLIST

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

An encrypted list of products added to your Wishlist.  
  
WISHLIST_CNT

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

The number of items in your Wishlist.  
  
Made.com

Made.com/Unboxed

Made.com/Blog

Made.com/One

| 

unboxed-referer

| 

First party

| 

Session

|    
  
unboxed-cookie-notification

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

These cookies are set to test and check for Cookie policy acceptance.  
  
unboxed-f-lat

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Used to find where the product uploaded by Unboxed user are located  
  
unboxed-f-lng

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Used to find where the product uploaded by Unboxed user are located  
  
unboxed-f-location

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Used to find where the product uploaded by Unboxed user are located  
  
unboxed-f-name

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Used to find where the product uploaded by Unboxed user are located  
  
unboxed-f-sort

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Used to find where the product uploaded by Unboxed user are located  
  
unboxed-f-zoom

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Used to find where the product uploaded by Unboxed user are located  
  
unboxed-locale

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Used to find where the product uploaded by Unboxed user are located  
  
unboxed-picture

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Used by Unboxed to display the product image on the map.  
  
unboxed-loggedin

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Used for logged in users  
  
unboxed-loggedhash

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Used for logged in users  
  
unboxed-loggedcreated

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Used for logged in users  
  
unboxed-likes

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Used by Unboxed to display the likes assigned to users  
  
X-TOKEN

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Used by Unboxed to identify the user  
  
_msuuid_uvqjkk36v0

| 

First party

| 

Persistent, 1 year

| 

This cookie is used to track the performance of our search marketing program. Information is recorded on gross bookings and search terms which is then communicated to our search marketing partner.  
  
_pk_id.•

| 

First party

| 

Persistent, 2 years

| 

User tracking cookie  
  
_pk_ses.•

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Avoid counting a person twice when we count how many people visit our website  
  
hl

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Tracks a session, i.e., how long you are on our website  
  
made_com_campaign_ts

|   |   |    
  
made_com_campaign

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Tracks response to campaign marketing  
  
made_com_country

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Tracks which of our country sites was selected.  
  
made_com_source

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Tracks response to source URL marketing  
  
made_responsive

| 

First party

| 

Session

|    
  
frontend

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Your session ID on the server.  
  
frontend_cid

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

An alternate website session id used by Magento for site caching, e.g. Varnish.  
  
_made_fetch_state_  
*country_code*

| 

First party

| 

Persistent, 14 days

| 

Country specific, set to retrieve data (total, quantity) from customer basket via AJAX. Contains no sensitive data.  
  
_made_quote_state_  
*country_code*

| 

First party

| 

Persistent, 1 year

| 

Country specific, set to retrieve data (total, quantity) from customer basket via AJAX. Contains no sensitive data.  
  
_made_com_is_first_visit

| 

First party

| 

Persistent, 3 months

| 

Tracks whether this is the first visit of the site.  
  
ss_opts

| 

First party

| 

Session

|    
  
zte2095

| 

First party

| 

Session

|    
  
_dc_gtm_UA-#

| 

First party

| 

Session

|    
  
__btr_em

| 

First party

| 

Session

|    
  
__btr_id

| 

First party

| 

Session

|    
  
__utmx

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

This cookie is for controlling content  
  
__utmxx

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

This cookie is used to prevent a user from seeing different versions of the same page during testing.  
  
pages_viewed_default

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Counts how many pages were visited in the user's session. we use it to show a popup on third page  
  
_subscription_popup_shown

| 

First party

| 

Persistent, 3 days

| 

Generated during AB testing  
  
_cae

| 

First party

| 

Session

|    
  
_#uid

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Stores a user identifier (only within a site). This notifies us when an anonymous user on is a repeat visitor, but does not profile the user  
  
_#sess

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Stores information about the session  
  
_#env

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Flags whether the environment variables (screen size, browser etc.) need to be collected again.  
  
_#srchist

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Stores the history of traffic sources the user has arrived to the site by.  
  
_#vdf

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Stores the visit definition – its type, number of visits, expiry  
  
_#tsa

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Stores the referrer details to avoid duplicate Landing events.  
  
zte2095

| 

First party

| 

Session

|    
  
_cs_cvars

| 

First party

| 

Session

|    
  
_cs_r

| 

First party

| 

Session

|    
  
_cs_s

| 

First party

| 

Session

|    
  
_cs_v

| 

First party

| 

Session

|    
  
member.uid

| 

First party

| 

Session

|    
  
pages_viewed_default

| 

First party

| 

Session

|    
  
comment_author_email_#

| 

First party

| 

Session

|    
  
woocommerce_items_  
in_cart

woocommerce_cart_  
hash

wp_woocommerce_  
session_#

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

The first two cookies contain information about the cart as a whole and helps WooCommerce know when the cart data changes. The final cookie (wp_woocommerce_session_) contains a unique code for each customer so that it knows where to find the cart data in the database for each customer. No personal information is stored within these cookies.  
  
_#slid

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Unique sale ID, tracks the point when a contact us form is clicked on the site. - See more at: //www.worldpay.com/uk/worldpay-cookies#sthash.iyVI03IO.dpuf  
  
__distillery

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

This cookie is used by our video player to remember where you are in a video so that if playback is interrupted (for example, by losing your internet connection) then you can get right back to where you left off. fast.wistia.com  
  
_cs_id

| 

First party

| 

Persistent

|    
  
TW_SESSION_ID

TW_SESSION_SEQUENCE

TW_VISITOR_ID

| 

First party

| 

Persistent

| 

This Cookie allow us to remember your preference regarding cookies  
  
etc_test_

| 

First party

| 

Session

| 

Provides insights into the visitor journey, allowing us to analyse this and improve our website by providing our visitors information that they’re looking for in a way which is useful to them.  
  
###  PERFORMANCE COOKIES 

**Cookie Provider**

| 

**Cookie Name**

| 

**First or third party cookie**

| 

**Persistent or session cookie**

| 

**Purpose cookie used for**  
  
---|---|---|---|---  
  
Pingdom

| 

__cfduid

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent, 1 Year

| 

CloudFlare, website performance monitoring  
  
Cedexis

| 

cdx_ses_1_16093

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Monitoring page load speed  
  
visid_incap_888004

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Security and acceleration  
  
incap_ses_151_888004

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Security and acceleration  
  
utmvmVEuIOck

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

Security and acceleration  
  
__cfduid

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Service to identify trusted web traffic.  
  
ContextWEb

| 

pb_rtb_ev

sto-id-20480-bh

V

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

Registers anonymised user data, such as IP address, geographical location, visited websites, and what ads the user has clicked, with the purpose of optimising ad display based on the user's movement on websites that use the same ad network.  
  
Marin

| 

_msuuid

| 

Third Party

| 

Session

| 

These cookies collect information about how visitors use a website. These cookies don’t collect information that identifies a visitor  
  
Liverail

| 

lr_uid

lr_uds

| 

Third Party

| 

Persistent, 3 months

| 

Regulates synchronisation of user identification and exchange of user data between various ad services.  
  
lijit.com

| 

ljt_reader

_lijit_retarget_rtb_

_ljtrtb_#

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

Analytics, multivariate testing, and site optimisation.  
  
Infectious Media

| 

khaos

idb

anj

c

CfP

put_2138

put_2149

put_2931

rpb

sess

uuid2

| 

Thirs party

| 

Session

| 

Google Analytics helps us collect and analyse visitor information such as browser usage, new visitor numbers, response to marketing activity and shopping times. That information helps us to improve the website and your shopping experience, and to make our marketing campaigns relevant.  
  
SiteImprove

| 

ASP.NET_SessionId

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

This cookie is used purely to track the sequence of pages a visitor looks at during a visit to the site. The user is not personally identifiable. This information can be used to reduce user journeys, and enable visitors to find relevant information quicker.  
  
DC Storm Analytics

| 

_#env

_#sess

_#srchist

_#tsa

_#uid

_#vdf

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

DC Storm Analytics will do the following:

Flags whether the environment variables (screen size, browser etc.) need to be collected again.

Stores information about the session.

Stores the history of traffic sources the user has arrived to the site.

Stores the referrer details to avoid duplicate Landing events

Stores a user identifier (only within a site). This notifies us when an anonymous user on is a repeat visitor, but does not profile the user

Stores the visit definition – its type, number of visits, expiry.  
  
New Relic

| 

nr-data.net JSESSIONID

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

This cookie tracks the number of user sessions to manage Website resources to improve performance and the user experience  
  
Keyade

|   | 

Third party

| 

Persistent

|    
  
Leguide

|   | 

Third party

| 

Persistent

|    
  
Productsup

|   | 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Track User for attribution modelling  
  
summit

|   | 

Third party

| 

Persistent

|    
  
Zopim

| 

__zlcmid

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

We use Zopim to provide live customer service chat on our Site. Zopim requires two cookies: the first cookie stores Zopim Live Chat ID to identify the device during visits. The second stores user’s preference to disable Live Chat.  
  
Google

| 

HSID

SAPISID

SID

SAPISID

APISID

SSID

HSID

NID

PREF

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Google set a number of cookies on any page that includes a Google Map. While we have no control over the cookies set by Google, they appear to include a mixture of pieces of information to measure the number and behaviour of Google Maps users.  
  
DMP

|   | 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

DMP is a series of one-stop multi-media advertising platform, and its responsibilities include:

RECORD DATA:

Traffic Sources

Cookie

FB Id

Operation Record

SAVE DATA:

All the data collected are segmented and saved for analysis

ANALYZE DATA:

Analysis, sorting out the visual information chart with statistics

IDENTIFY TARGET:

Mining goal

Finishing population

Management portfolio

Provides objective

Provide a target for DSP  
  
###  FUNCTIONALITY COOKIES 

**Cookie Provider**

| 

**Cookie name**

| 

**First or third party cookie**

| 

**Persistent or session cookie**

| 

**Purpose cookie used for**  
  
---|---|---|---|---  
  
Pingdom

| 

PRUM_EPISODES

| 

Third Party

| 

Persistent, 1 Year

| 

This cookie measures the page load speed to identify pages that don't perform as fast as we would like, and fix the speed to ensure that you have pleasant site experience.  
  
Google Tag Manager

| 

_dc_gtm_UA-12859730-1

| 

First Party

| 

Persistent, 3 months

| 

A unique identifier given to each browser to track user interactions with the website.  
  
_gali

| 

Third Party

| 

Session

| 

Google Analyitics – Cookies of third parties used to collect information on how users use the website to guarantee the best accuracy in the reporting activity. Cookies collect data in anonymous form, including the number of website visitors, how they have reached the website and which pages they visited.  
  
gtm_user_created_at

| 

Third Party

| 

Persistent, 1 week

|    
  
gtm_user_email

| 

Third Party

| 

Persistent, 1 week

|    
  
gtm_user_id

| 

Third Party

| 

Persistent, 1 week

| 

Used to Join sessions crossed devices  
  
Google Analytics

| 

__zlcmid

| 

Third Party

| 

Persistent, 1 year

| 

These cookies are used by Google Analytics to obtain information of how users use Made.com. We use this information to generate reports and to improve user experience in Made.com - Analytical Cookies  
  
_gat_UA-12859730-1

| 

Third Party

|   |    
  
NID

| 

Third Party

|   | 

Could cover a multitude of sins but they definitely place cookies if you have embedded Google Maps into your pages.  
  
_gali

| 

Third Party

|   | 

This cookie is typically written to the browser upon the first visit. If the cookie has been deleted by the browser operator, and the browser subsequently visits made.com, a new _gali cookie is written with a different unique ID. In most cases, this cookie is used to determine unique visitors to siniat.co.uk and it is updated with each page view. Additionally, this cookie is provided with a unique ID that Google Analytics uses to ensure both the validity and accessibility of the cookie as an extra security measure.  
  
idb

| 

Third Party

| 

Persistent, 1 year

| 

These cookies are set by google analytics.

More about google analytics is available here.  
  
Google Website Optimiser

| 

__utmx

__utmxx

| 

Third Party

| 

Persistent, 1 year

| 

These cookies are used by Google Analytics to obtain information of how users use Made.com. We use this information to generate reports and to improve user experience in Made.com - Analytical Cookies  
  
_gat_UA-12859730-1

| 

Third Party

|   |    
  
idb

| 

Third Party

| 

Persistent, 1 year

| 

These cookies are set by google analytics.  
  
GetClicky

.bm23.com

.bronto.com

| 

__cfduid

| 

Third Party

| 

Persistent, 1 year

| 

Web analytics statistic tool  
  
__cfduid

| 

Third Party

| 

Persistent, 1 year

| 

Web analytics statistic tool  
  
Sharethrough

| 

stx_user_id

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent, 1 month

| 

Analytics, multivariate testing, and site optimisation.  
  
###  ADVERTISING COOKIES 

**Cookie Name**

| 

**First or third party cookie**

| 

**Persistent or session cookie**

| 

**Purpose cookie used for**  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
.ih.adscale.de/ adscale.de

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
3Lift.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent, 3 month

| 

Used to monitor search behaviour  
  
Adform

| 

Third party

|   | 

These cookies are used to collect data about the websites and individual pages that users visit both on and off our websites (which might indicate, for example, your interests and other attributes).  
  
adaptv.advertising.com

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
.adnxs.com

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

Adnxs.com is run by AppNexus, a company that provides technology, data and analytics to help companies buy and sell online display advertising.  
  
ADTech

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent, 1 Month

| 

This ADTECH cookie allows the ad server to check if you accept cookies  
  
adtech.de

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
Adwords

| 

Third party

|   | 

We use Google Adwords Conversion tracker which uses cookies to help us determine how many people who clicked on our Google Ads end up contacting us through the website.  
  
Affiliate Windows

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
ARM

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
Bidswitch.net

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent, 1 Year

| 

This cookie regulates synchronisation of user identification and exchange of user data between various ad services.  
  
Bing

| 

Third party

| 

Unknown

| 

Bing’s cookies can also track and remember searches that you have made.

This cookie is widely used my Microsoft as a unique user identifier. It can be set by embedded Microsoft scripts. Widely believed to sync across many different Microsoft domains, allowing user tracking.  
  
Burstnet

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent, 3 months

| 

Online advertising networks use Cookies to track users across web sites and to measure ad impressions and clickthroughs.  
  
Casale Media

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

Collects anonymous data related to the user's visits to the website, such as the number of visits, average time spent on the website and what pages have been loaded, with the purpose of displaying targeted ads.  
  
Connexity

| 

Third party

| 

Unknown

|    
  
Criteo

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

Criteo specializes in creating personalized advertisements and to provide users with a seamless online experience, we may link your identifiers on the different browsers and environments you are using (“ID syncing”).

But never willingly store data that would allow identification of a person (such as name, surname, phone number, address, etc.). Criteo collects data related to your browsing activity through cookies or advertising IDs  
  
DataOnDemand

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
DCMNTV

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
DFA (DoubleClick)

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness. A floodlight tag is an image pixel that is created within DFA and resides on the Advertiser’s webpage  
  
DMP

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
DOUBLECLICK.NET

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

This cookie is used for re-targeting, optimisation, reporting and attribution of online adverts.  
  
Ebay

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
go.flx1.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
Hi-Media

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness - An advertising targeting cookie will permit to identify different criteria for the purpose of managing the display of advertising campaigns  
  
Impdesk.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
Improve Digital BV

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent, 3 months

| 

This Third Party tracking allows our media owners to better understand user profiles and enables them and us to tailor our adverts to make them more relevant to our customers’ needs.E98  
  
Leverate

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
Liverail

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent, 3 months

| 

This site uses the buttons LIKE and SHARE to interact on Facebook. Facebook itself uses the services of third party LiveRail to show advertising in line with your interests. Registers a unique user ID to target advertisements in the video platform, LiveRail.  
  
Moebel

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
NL 24u

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
Piwik (TV Squared)

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent, 2 years

| 

This contains a 64-byte int UUID that is generated when the cookie is created. It contains a timestamp of the cookie creation date in UTC, which is used to process the days it took for goal conversion. It contains a visits count that is updated when a _pk_ses cookie is created and this is used to calculate Visits to conversion. It contains a timestamp of the last page view of the last visit before this visit, which is used to process Days since last visit and Days to purchase.  
  
PUBMATIC

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent, 1 months

| 

Pubmatic uses this cookie to correlate our user IDs with those of our partners (such as demand side platform clients or other advertising technology companies). We pass the information stored by the partner in this cookie to the partner when it is considering whether to purchase advertisements. This enables the partner to make better decisions about whether to display an advertisement to you.  
  
Quantum

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
Qubit

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent, 1 month

| 

Registers anonymised user data, such as IP address, geographical location, visited websites, and what ads the user has clicked, with the purpose of optimising ad display based on the user's movement on websites that use the same ad network.  
  
Taboola.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

This cookie keeps track of user segmentation.  
  
swid.switchads.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
Tradedoubler

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

radedoubler's tracking technology allows you to track and reward publisher activity in a way that suits you.,

Pixel tracking is the most common type of tracking as it is quick to implement and provides instant data for advertisers and publishers. It is our preferred tracking method and we would recommend it wherever possible. It consists of two elements:

Redirect page: All Tradedoubler traffic will pass through this page before directing the user onto the requested page on your site. This page will handle Tradedoubler's unique tracking identifier (TDUID) and cookie setting tasks.

Confirmation page: The tracking pixel (also known as the tracking or conversion tag) must be displayed on the confirmation page. This is the page immediately after the transaction has been completed (e.g. confirming the order has been placed).  
  
TV Squared

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent, 2.5 year

| 

TV Squared allows us to track the effectiveness of our TV advertising. TV Squared collects information anonymously including the number of visitors to the site, which site or search engine they have come from and the pages they have visited. TV Squared do not collect any personally identifiable information.  
  
Twenga

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
Ultimatefeed

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
Wemaster

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
Yahoo

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

Yahoo’s cookies can also track and remember searches that you have made. Yahoo has paid advertisements included in their search results.  
  
.adtechus.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
.advertising.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
atdmt.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
.atemda.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Three persistent cookies to analyse user behaviour in order to provide targeted commercial content. The cookies are stored for two months.  
  
btrll.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Used for video ads. Makes it possible to affect selected user groups with targeted messages.  
  
1rx.io

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
rubiconproject.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
adsrvr.org

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
bat.r.msn.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
msn.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
ad.360yield.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
t.c4tw.net

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
smartadserver.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
openx.net

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
Google

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
bat.bing.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
ligadx.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
teads.tv

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
yieldlab.net

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
emailretargeting.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
.spotxchange.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
www.tag4arm.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
www3.smartadserver.com

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
geo-um.btrll.com

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

Advertising and marketing effectiveness  
  
###  SOCIAL MEDIA COOKIES 

**Cookie Provider**

| 

**Cookie name**

| 

**First or third party cookie**

| 

**Persistent or session cookie**

| 

**Purpose cookie used for**  
  
---|---|---|---|---  
  
Facebook

| 

locale

lu

fr

x-src

datr

| 

Thirs party

| 

Persistent

| 

These are Facebook cookies that determine whether you are logged in to facebook during your browser session. They also allow you to like a page and record the number of times a page has been liked. Some also prevents the creation of fake accounts and spammy accounts. Lower the risk of users’ accounts being taken over by other people.

Protect users’ content against theft. Prevent DDoS (distributed denial of service) attacks that could make Facebook inaccessible to some users.  
  
Twitter

| 

guest_id

_twitter_sess

external_referer

ua

| 

Thirs party

| 

Persistent, 2 Years

| 

Twitter cookie that appears on pages where ‘Tweet’ button is used and serves as your unique identification number associated with Twitter  
  
Pinterest

| 

_pinterest_cm

_pinterest_referrer

_auth

csrftoken

_pinterest_sess

_pinterest_cm

| 

Third party

| 

Persisten, 1 year

| 

Used by Pinterest to track the usage of services.  
  
Google

| 

GAPS

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent, 2 years

| 

Google set a number of cookies on any page that includes a Google Calendar. While we have no control over the cookies set by Google, they appear to include a mixture of pieces of information to measure the number and behaviour of Google Calendar users, as well as information about which calendar you are viewing, and which tab you are currently on.  
  
GALX

| 

Third party

| 

Session

|    
  
Youtube

| 

VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE

| 

Third party

| 

Persistent, 1 year

| 

We use YouTube to embed a selection of videos on our blog as well as our ‘About Us’ section. The embedded videos do not set cookies themselves and can be played with no cookies set. However, if the ‘Share’ button is clicked YouTube will set these two cookies. The VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE cookie attempts to estimate your bandwidth and the use_hitbox cookie increments the ‘views’ counter on the YouTube video. These cookies don’t gather information that identifies a user.  
  
YSC

| 

Third party

| 

Session

| 

This cookie is set by the YouTube video service on pages with embedded YouTube video.  
  
PREF

|   | 

Persistent, 1 year

| 

This cookie is set by the YouTube video service on pages with embedded YouTube video.  
  
###  CHANGES 

Information about the cookies used by us may be updated from time to time, so please check back on a regular basis for any changes. The last modification date of this document is shown at the top of this page. 

###  QUESTIONS 

If you have any questions about our use of cookies, please contact us by email at [privacy@made.com](mailto:privacy@made.com).
